Michel Pomerantzeff

+351 93 777 1656 | michelpomerantzeff@gmail.com | Vila Nova de Gaia - Portugal

michelpomerantzeff.netlify.app | linkedin.com/in/michelpomerantzeff | github.com/MichelPomerantzeff

About

I am a Frontend Developer with excellent communication skills, a team spirit and a never-ending drive to learn, refine and expand my knowledge.

With regard to the projects I have built I focus on best practice, for instance writing organized, reusable and effective code. Moreover, I value responsive solutions and user-friendly experience.

Skills

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | ReactJS | Redux | Angular | Bootstrap | PostgreSQL | Firebase | Java | Git | Jira

Experience

Freelance Developer - Aug 2023 - Present

My freelance journey has provided me with valuable experience, enabling me to continuously expand my skill set while delivering high-quality software solutions tailored to each client's unique requirements. My ability to optimize performance and innovate with new features underscores my commitment to delivering exceptional results in the world of development.

Full Stack Developer intern at JUMIA - Feb 2023 - Aug 2023

As a Full Stack Developer, I collaborated closely with a cross-functional team to design and implement user-friendly and responsive web interfaces using Angular and TypeScript for the Frontend. On the backend, I contributed to the development of robust server-side functionality and APIs using Java and Spring Boot, emphasizing efficient data processing. I actively worked on authentication and authorization mechanisms to reinforce security and protect sensitive user data.

Moreover, I prioritized performance optimization, implementing fine-tuning and query optimization techniques to enhance API efficiency.

Projects

Food Ecommerce

Live demo | Github repo

Summary: React-firebase-hook facilitates the management of user state, keeping track of when they are logged in or logged out. Stripe API deals with creating and accepting card payment sources. Firebase for relational database schema allows for easy retrieval of product and order data.

Future implementation: Add geolocation API to locate user address. **Stack:** ReactJS | Redux | React Router | Firebase | Express | Stripe API

Movie App

Live demo | Github repo

Summary: Search for any movie, consult information about it (e.g. rating, cast, and plot), select the movie you want and add it to a watchlist or a list of watched movies.

Future implementation: Add user's own comments and rating to watched movies.

Stack: ReactJS | Redux | Costum Hooks | React Router | Firebase | TMDb API

Link Saver

Live demo | Github repo

Summary: Save information of online products such as name, price and link in an organized way. Filter bars make it easier for you to scan through your list of products and find specific ones.

Future implementation: Notification of price change and product availability.

Stack: ReactJS | Java | Spring Boot | PostgreSQL

Education

Scrimba - React 2021 - 2022

FreeCodeCamp - JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures 2021 - 2022

Udemy - Full Web Course with JavaScript - 2021

Estudonauta - JavaScript, HTML and CSS - 2020

UNIP - Bachelor in Physical Education 2010 - 2014

Languages

Portuguese - Native English - Fluent